Because there is a lot of fabric in the shirt, if you don't sew it, it may be inconvenient to wear it directly outside.
After inserting the T-shirt, remove the excess sleeves and make a V-shape according to our needs.
After pulling the middle point down and making a V-shape, press the control button to simulate.
Because the shirt is tight now, the T-shirt is large and loose, so it is easy to fit outside the shirt.
Then we can adjust the size of the shirt according to our needs.
Finally, reduce the particle diameter and the impact thickness a little bit.
After reducing, let's take a look at the shirt.
Now, it's the bottom of the shirt.
Not the bottom of the shirt.
The shoulder line is still relatively wide.
When we make some suits, the shoulders may be relatively narrow.
We can refer to the effect I made at the end.
You can see that the shoulders are relatively narrow.
So we can choose the front and back pieces at the same time, and then change them a little bit.
Let's change the front and back pieces together.
We can also make sure that the length is correct.
Otherwise, if you only change the front and back pieces and don't change them, there will be wrinkles here.
Because most of the wrinkles are caused by the irregularity of the sewing line.
Then let's take a look at this point on the side.
The waistband is generally relatively loose, so you can compare the 3D window effect on this side point.
Pull it a little bit bigger.
You can see that the waistband is a little bit loose.
After we adjust the bottom of the page, we can activate the inner layer.
Let's simulate it together.
The inner layer of this shirt, we can now put the previous one.
It's this gold silk.
The shrinkage is released.
Before that, I will change a different fabric color for this vest.
So it's more convenient for me to distinguish these two plates.
Then we take the waistline shrinkage from the previous 80 and return it to 100 step by step.
Now you can see that the outer waistband is simulated together.
So after we gradually return the inner layer shrinkage to 100,
the waistband is still on the outside of the shirt.
And it's very stable.
We don't need to do any other operations.
So this is what we have repeatedly emphasized.
If you want to make a multi-layer dress,
it's best to make the inner layer into a tight one.
Or at least make it look like it doesn't have a very obvious conflict with the outer layer.
So we usually use shrinkage to shrink it into a tight one.
Then we put the outer layer in.
Then we use the editor's round tool to adjust the curve of the bottom of the page.
Of course, you can adjust this according to your own preferences.
For me, because I was referring to the food chart at that time,
so I will try to make it as flat as possible here.
In 3D space, try to make it as flat as possible.
Then we can start to prepare for some other effects.
First of all, we can make it a rope.
And before that, you can change its physical properties to wool.
Because in general, this kind of thick set,
its horseshoe is made of this kind of wool.
So we can change the wool directly.
And then, when we were just imitating,
we saw that its back had some bones.
It is because we now put the lining of this shirt,
its shrinkage returns to 100,
you will see that the fabric of the shirt is a lot.
So it looks like it will have a lot of bones.
It will hold the horseshoe out.
So what can we add behind this shirt?
Is there any smart baby who knows what we are going to add?
That is, we are now equal to saying that
there is more fabric in the back of this plate.
We need to give it a little bit of fabric reduction.
But what about the back here?
We are very flat.
Right.
So we are going to add some ropes to the waist here.
Right, right.
It's a rope.
Because we only have a lot of fabric on the waist here.
So we just add a rope to it.
When you add a rope,
pay attention to where the widest position of the rope is.
It's in the thinnest position of our waist.
Because the thinnest place of the waist is the waist.
Right.
The thinnest place of the waist must have the least amount of fabric.
So we just dig a rope here.
But you can dig this rope a little bigger.
Because we have a principle when making clothes.
That is, you can dig a little more where you can't see it.
The rope is like this.
The rope is equivalent to digging a zero space on the board.
Then sew it up left and right.
Its function is to make your clothes more intimate.
If you don't know what a rope is,
you can go and take a look at our previous episode of Jingsheng Yi.
The rabbit.
The rabbit girl's suit.
There is a detailed talk about what a rope is.
Okay.
Then we put these two boards a little further away from each other in the 2D window.
Then select the middle part.
Right click to select the board outline expansion.
Then set its diameter here.
We are going to start making the door brim.
The door brim is used to place the button.
Because our door brim is basically set up with a button.
So we have to put this amount out.
Here you can choose to make the inner line or not.
Okay.
What about the side angle here?
We can set it as perpendicular.
It's a right angle.
Or it's extend.
Of course, I recommend that you use extend.
Because in general, your door brim is like this.
It won't suddenly have a right angle here.
The default in the software is perpendicular.
It's the shape of the right angle.
It will be supplemented by a rectangle here.
Remember to change it to extend here.
Okay.
Then we have one more piece of fabric on the board.
According to the male outfit in real life.
The left side is usually outside.
So we can pull these two boards a little further in the 3D space.
Otherwise, the part we just extended is overlapping.
There will be a conflict between the boards.
They will have some interaction.
Let's arrange them first.
After arranging, there was a seam line in the middle before.
Don't forget to delete it later.
Then in the middle, we can adjust its position according to the need.
Then the point used to extend before.
We can convert it to a free curve point.
Or move this point.
Let it form a circular curve.
Here you can see that I just converted this point to a free curve point.
Then delete this point.
Do you know if this point is originally a straight line point?
I delete this point.
What will happen to this curve?
For example, there is a straight line point in the middle of this curve.
Then I delete the straight line point.
What will happen to it?
It will be a straight line point.
This point will be a straight line point.
This is a straight line point.
That's right.
Tatika is right.
If there is a straight line point on this line,
you don't choose to convert the straight line point to a curve point,
but delete this straight line point directly.
This curve will be left straight.
So everyone should pay attention.
The steps I will use must be to convert this point to a curve point first.
Then delete this curve point separately.
to delete one of the curve points,
so that it won't affect the other curve points.
Next, we can see that
this point is the point that we automatically generated
by using the expansion and expansion of the panel line.
We will add a button
along this point.
Because this way we can guarantee
that it is just right to wear it.
Because we just sewed the middle line together here,
so you just add a button
along the position of this line
before.
So that when we button it up later,
it will still be in this position.
Can you understand?
Then after we select the button,
in the process of ctrl-c and ctrl-v,
press the right button to enter the specific value
to copy multiple buttons.
Then we can select
a row of buttons,
press the right button to copy the button eyes
and then press the left button to copy the button eyes.
In this way,
these two buttons and the button eyes
are symmetrical.
Their positions are also symmetrical.
Because we created the button
on the middle line just now,
so the button eyes here
are also on the middle line.
Then we use the ctrl-c button
to connect them together.
Their positions are still
where we sewed just now.
Then we delete
the extra sewing line.
This sewing line must be wrong.
Then we simulate it again.
Look, it's very stable now.
And the position of the ctrl-c button
is still where we sewed just now.
The overall size of the panel
is not affected.
Can you understand?
Then you can switch to
the material column of the ctrl-c button,
find the type of this ctrl-c button
and adjust its width
and thickness
according to your needs.
OK.
Next,
according to the reference,
the position of the ctrl-c button
in the picture I referred to
is all on the left.
So we need to
set the position of the ctrl-c button.
The position of the ctrl-c button
is not a property
belonging to the ctrl-c button.
Because when you select the ctrl-c button,
it is in the material column of the ctrl-c button.
After you select
a ctrl-c button type,
then go to the property editor,
what you can adjust
is the shape of this ctrl-c button,
instead of the interaction between it
and the ctrl-c button.
So at this time,
we need to select the move ctrl-c button
to select.
And you need to select the ctrl-c button,
then you can set the position of the ctrl-c button.
As you can see,
the ctrl-c button will move to the side.
We adjust the position
of the ctrl-c button
in this way.
Do you understand?
Then we can switch to
the material column of the ctrl-c button
to change the shape
of the ctrl-c button.
Next,
we can start
to make the guide.
Of course, in the middle,
we have made a
corner effect like this.
Then,
before we make the guide,
we can put it on the waist first.
As you can see,
this vest is actually
a little bit too close to the waist.
So we can click on the plate
and add a straight line
near its waist.
Then move the straight line
a little bit inside
so that its waist line
is a little bit closer to the waist.
Just a little bit.
Then we can start
to make the ctrl-c button.
For the ctrl-c button,
I actually came here
based on the reference.
If you refer to it,
there will be a cut line
for the ctrl-c button.
Because adding the ctrl-c button
is to make the vest
a little bit closer to the waist,
it is not the same.
Because the curve on the side
needs to be aligned.
But if you add the ctrl-c button,
you don't need to consider
the problem of the side line.
You can just sew the ctrl-c button
to the left and right.
So the ctrl-c button
is more convenient
than the movement point
on the right side.
Because it has a slow transition
to the front and back.
Then,
the ctrl-c button
is a little bit wider.
So you can see
that there are some
creases here.
You can see that there are no creases in the middle.
But there are some
cross-shaped creases here.
That means that
you have dug too much
fabric on the ctrl-c button.
Then the waist is tight here
and the other parts are very loose.
Then you can
make the ctrl-c button
a little bit narrower.
You can see that
there are no creases here.
You can even make the ctrl-c button
a little bit narrower.
Just a little bit.
But if your ctrl-c button
is too narrow,
there will be a problem.
Usually,
the ctrl-c button will be
connected to a pocket
and cut to the bottom.
You can see that
there are a lot of
ctrl-c buttons
that have this kind of structure.
But if you cut this line
at this time,
it will tell you
that the distance between the lines
is too close.
Please separate the points.
Have you ever encountered this problem?
It reminds you
that the line is too close to the line.
Please separate the lines
and cut to the bottom.
It will show you
that when you cut this line,
it will form a corner.
This corner will cause
the corner here to be
smaller than 20 degrees.
So,
when we cut this ctrl,
you can pull
these two points out
a little bit
so that this corner
is 20 degrees larger.
It may sound a little
complicated,
but this is our
protection mechanism
for creating a board.
Because if your board is very thin,
and because the default
particle diameter is 20,
it can't satisfy
the corner that is
smaller than 20 degrees.
So there is such a mechanism
in our software.
When your corner is smaller than 20 degrees,
you can't cut it.
After you cut it,
you can change the ctrl back.
That's it.
There is no problem.
So,
when you are doing this,
you have to pay attention.
If you see this spring,
you have to pull
this point
a little bit.
Don't have a corner
that is smaller than 20 degrees.
Then,
you can turn it into
a slow crossing.
Can you understand?
The longer the crossing,
the slower the crossing.
the longer the crossing.
Then,
we can move the point.
Hello,
the rich woman you can't get.
Let's move
the point of the crossing.
Why do I move
the point of the crossing?
Did you see that
the crossing is crooked?
And it is more obvious,
right?
The crossing is
crooked here.
Because the crossing
is here.
Then,
we cut the two points here.
After that,
the crossing is crooked now.
Right?
This line looks shorter.
This line looks longer.
If you sew it up,
there may be some pull.
So,
first,
you can pull the two points down
a little bit.
Then,
move these two points to the middle.
Let it look like a left and right symmetry.
It may sound a bit boring.
But,
you can see that
the left and right lines
are almost the same length.
OK.
Then,
let's compare the left and right symmetry
of the crossing.
You can see that
there is no
very obvious pull.
There are some pull effects.
It doesn't matter.
Even if you don't adjust
this,
you can still make it.
Hello, hello,
Annie Radon.
Hello, hello.
OK.
Next,
we use
the 3D drawing tool
to draw a line
directly on the board
to make a pocket line.
OK.
Then, we choose
the 3D drawing tool.
You can change it to the 3D drawing tool
or change it to the 3D drawing tool.
OK.
Here,
we delete
the excess straight lines.
Then,
because we want to make a pocket line,
now,
this line crosses
the line line.
So,
we need to delete
this line
and delete it.
OK.
After deleting it,
pay attention to the pocket.
Generally,
it is on the widest side of the line.
Then,
we move the straight line point
over.
OK.
After moving it,
we refer to the effect
in the 3D window.
Then,
there is an inner line.
We will make a pocket line
on the base of the inner line.
Then,
we can block
the wide line
in the middle of the line.
Sometimes,
when you make the board,
it may not be neat
and neat.
Sometimes,
the widest line
can block the point
of the pocket line.
Do you understand?
OK. Then,
we draw the inner line on both sides.
After selecting these two lines,
refer to the length
in the shape editor
to draw a rectangle
and sew it up.
OK.
Are you listening?
Hello?
There are back-up.
If we want to make a multi-step
poverty,
what shortcut should we use?
What shortcut should we use?
Because I just used
one and multi-step
poverty here.
What key should we press
to make multi-step poverty?
We add it to the outside quickly.
This board will be arranged automatically.
That's right.
It's shift.
OK.
Remember to check if the points of the inner line you draw are connected.
Because the inner line of the empty heart is separated,
many times I will forget if they are together.
Sometimes you see that the line is shaking in a certain position,
it is very likely that the inner line you draw is separated,
and then their heads are not connected,
but your line of the powder is connected,
there will be such a problem.
It's not Alt, it's Shift.
Then we can lengthen the inner line appropriately,
and then lengthen the edges of the pocket at the same time,
so that their width can be increased a little.
Then you see that I didn't connect it to the rope here,
so it will cause some simulation problems.
There are some strange places that look like a powder line.
Then we can modify it here.
If you want to move the whole position of this pocket,
you must remember to select all the points and lines related to this pocket,
and then press Shift together, or press Alt to move.
Then we move this point a little bit to the side,
because I just said that it is best to be symmetrical to the left and right of the rope,
and not to be tilted to one side.
Okay, because our powder line,
we have made a lot of adjustments to this line just now,
so we have to re-create our powder line.
Because sometimes this powder line,
when we sew a whole section and multiple sections together,
there is no break in the middle,
and there is no way to follow the break,
so the length of the left and right seam lines is different.
So everyone should pay attention to this.
Then we do the back piece again.
Because the one I referred to,
it is made of an adhesive structure,
that is to say, although its clip is made of the same layer,
but it has a layer on the outside that is a bit like silk.
So let's merge the back piece here first,
and we have to cancel the face movement of this symmetrical line in the middle,
otherwise you can't cut the dragon layer.
Okay, here you can tell me,
if I want to cut a layer and make a double layer structure now,
should I choose the outer layer of the dragon layer or the inner layer of the dragon layer?
Let me give you two seconds to think about it.
Okay, I see that some people say the outer layer and some people say the inner layer.
In fact, we should choose the inner layer.
Why?
Because we have a button outside now, right?
Since we have a button,
if we cut the dragon to the outer layer,
will the back piece and the button have a gap, right?
Because the button is now outside, right?
If you cut the dragon to the outer layer,
it will definitely bump into the button.
If the back piece and the button have a bump,
it will be unstable.
So we choose the inner layer of the dragon and it is more convenient,
and it is a more stable choice.
Do you understand?
Well, I have a feeling that I may talk about it until 12 o'clock today.
Okay, look, if we cut the dragon to the inner layer now,
we will encounter another problem at this time.
That is, is there a gap inside?
If we cut the dragon to the outer layer,
it will bump into the button, right?
So we have to start to layer it now.
Because in this case, it can identify it faster,
and it doesn't want to bump into it.
Well, no, we can't use reverse activation here.
If you use reverse activation,
will it just go through the button directly?
It can't be covered outside the button.
Then we will lose the meaning of loading the button into the button.
So we have to layer the button to the outer layer of the button, right?
That's why we need to freeze the shirt,
and then give it according to the level.
First of all, we first choose the inner layer of the dragon to the inner layer.
Give it a level of 1.
After giving it a level of 1,
it can be worn outside the shirt.
Then we change the level of the outer vest to 2,
and then simulate it.
Then it will be simulated very stable.
Here we are patient,
wait a minute,
take a look.
After it is simulated stable,
we can activate the shirt in the most inside,
and then simulate it together.
The advantage of doing this is that it can prevent the unstable formation caused by some strange changes in the atmosphere.
After we use the layer,
and after we wear it,
it is best to remember to simulate these frozen versions together.
Just let them interact once,
it can also prevent some instability.
After doing it, change the layer level to 0.
Don't forget,
because sometimes forgetting to change the layer level,
it may not affect you,
but it may affect you occasionally.
For example, you forgot to use the layer level,
then it may go through directly.
Right?
Okay, do you still remember?
Our previous version is symmetrical.
Then in order to create this inner layer, the curtain layer,
So we canceled the link.
Right?
This is why we can now change the internal and external layers at the same time.
Because this version is also a problem with symmetrical editing.
Symmetrical editing does not allow the operation of curtain layers.
The difference between frozen and anti-activation,
we uploaded a video before.
You can check it out if you have time.
I won't talk much about it.
Simply put, it's the same as the ACM version.
So this is the reason for the difference between the cold and anti-activation version.
In other words, if a board is frozen, it will collide with other boards.
Although these two versions, Freeze and Reactive Fire,
both maintain the current state of the board,
but if a board is frozen, it will collide with other boards.
They will not collide directly.
But if it is Reactive Fire, because it has no collision,
other boards will pass through this board.
They are all clothes worn on people, right?
Then you can't let them go through directly like this.
Then because of the outer layer of this board,
we want to do a different effect with the inner layer.
Because wool is usually flat and hard,
a big wrinkle,
I hope that the outer layer will form a small wrinkle.
So here,
my new creation,
I created a fabric,
I copied a fabric,
and then I changed it to Cotton Satin,
which looks a bit like a silk fabric.
At the same time, I will add a gold-like shrink to the outer layer,
and increase its shrink to 100.
Because the gold-like shrink increases the wrinkle in the vertical direction,
so we increase the shrink to 100 here in the gold-like area.
So its fabric,
because its grid is larger,
so its fabric looks more,
so it will produce some horizontal wrinkles.
Here,
friends who don't understand,
do you understand what this shrink is?
If you don't,
we will continue to talk about it.
Because you have to be vertical,
it is equivalent to lengthening the vertical direction of this board.
If you change the gold-like shrink,
if you change the tail-like shrink,
it is to lengthen in the horizontal direction,
to widen it.
So here we lengthen the outer board in the vertical direction,
and then because it is sewn together with the inner layer,
so we will produce some wrinkles.
But not all conditions can be used in this way,
because when you cut the dragon layer,
its wrinkle line is a whole circle,
then you just lengthen the board in the vertical direction,
but it will actually be divided into this board.
So if it is a more standardized operation,
you should delete this wrinkle line.
But in fact,
I took a look,
I think this effect is also OK.
Because the back is less wrinkled here,
the waist is more wrinkled here,
it is the effect I want,
so I didn't change this wrinkle line.
As for the principle,
why must the wrinkle line be changed from a whole circle to one by one?
Because you want the wrinkle to be produced in the vertical direction,
but if you sew it in a whole circle,
although the shape of our board has changed,
because if you change this shrink,
the shape changes in the vertical direction,
but its amount will be divided.
So usually,
we will change the wrinkle line here,
sew here,
then under the leaf,
sew under the leaf,
sew the side,
so that you can ensure that it is in the vertical direction.
But here,
if the effect is OK,
it is OK.
So in fact,
all our operations,
you use the effect as the standard.
You listen to me here to tell you the theory,
if you think it is very boring,
it doesn't matter,
you just follow yourself,
just think this effect is OK,
you just use that effect.
All right,
you don't have to force yourself,
you just have to do it very, very accurately.
It's just that there are some operating habits,
it's best to optimize it.